Peter Fallon - Gallery Press collection, circa 1967-1998
Emory University
- Printed material, 1960s-1990s, Series 5; Boxes 177-193
  - Gallery Press materials, Subseries 5.2; Boxes 187-189
    - Catalogues - Design to 1985 (Box 187, Folder 1)
    - Catalogues - Design to 1985 (Box 187, Folder 2)
    - Catalogues - Design since 1985 (Box 187, Folder 3)
    - Catalogues - Design since 1985 (Box OP81)
    - Catalogues - Design 1992 (Box 187, Folder 4)
    - Catalogues - Design 1992 (Box 187, Folder 5)
    - Catalogues (Printed) through 1985 (Box 188, Folder 1)
    - Catalogues (Printed) since 1985 (Box 188, Folder 2)
    - Mailings (Box 188, Folder 3)
    - Press Releases (Box 188, Folder 4)
    - Promotions - Booksellers, Collectors (Box 188, Folder 5)
    - Readings - Design (Box 188, Folder 6)
    - Readings - Design (Box OP82)
    - Readings 1974-1985 (Box 188, Folder 7)
    - Readings1986-May 1991 (Box 188, Folder 8)
    - Readings - Belfast and Dublin, 26 and 28 October, 1991 (Box 188, Folder 9)
    - Readings November 1991-1997 (Box 188, Folder 10)
    - Readings - The National Gallery of Ireland (1984-1988) (Box 188, Folder 11)
    - Reading Guest Book, 2/12/80 (Box 189, Folder 1)
    - Reading Guest Book, 3/10/91 (Box 189, Folder 2)
    - Reprints 1997 (Box 189, Folder 3)
    - Reviews - Correspondence, Etc. (Box 189, Folder 4)
    - Reviews - Correspondence, Etc. (Box 189, Folder 5)
    - Reviews - Promotional materials (Box 189, Folder 6)
    - Reviews - Records (Box 189, Folder 7)
    - Stationery, Forms, etc. (proofs) (Box 189, Folder 8)
  - General printed material, Series 5.3; Boxes 190-192
    - Newsclippings and Periodicals
    - Literary Newsclippings, 1970s (Box 190, Folder 1)
    - Literary Newsclippings, 1980s (Box 190, Folder 2)
    - Literary Newsclippings, 1980s (Box 190, Folder 3)
    - Literary Newsclippings, 1990s (Box 190, Folder 4)
    - Literary Newsclippings, 1990s (Box 190, Folder 5)
    - Newsclippings, 1970s (Box 190, Folder 6)
    - Newsclippings, 1980s (Box 190, Folder 7)
    - Newsclippings, 1990s (Box 190, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous Poems, Short Stories, etc. (Box 190, Folder 9)
    - Eirigh vol. 68 no. 3 (March 1970) (Box 190, Folder 10)
    - Gun vol. 6 (Box 190, Folder 11)
    - Haughey, Charles J., "The Taoiseeach, Mr. Charles J. Haughey T.D., and the Arts" [Speech to Aosdiana and Irish Times Interview on the Arts, 1990] (Box 190, Folder 12)
    - Henry, Adrian, The Entry of Christ into Liverpool in 1964 (Box 190, Folder 13)
    - Inherited Poetry Magazine no. 7 (n.d.) (Box 190, Folder 14)
    - Murphy, Hayden, "A Wish for Ireland" Broadside produced by the Citizens Committee (Box 190, Folder 15)
    - Pushbike no. 7 (1972) (Box 190, Folder 16)
    - Pushbike no. 8 (1972) [2 copies] (Box 190, Folder 17)
    - Resurgence: Journal of the Fourth World vol. 5 no. 1 (March-April 1974) (Box 190, Folder 18)
    - "The Small Press Scene" supplement to Second Aeon no. 10 (Box 190, Folder 19)
    - The Spark Issue 7 (November 1994) (Box 190, Folder 20)
    - Underground (n.d.) (Box 190, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous Newspapers and Periodicals (Box 191)
    - Promotional Material [other publishers]
    - Advertisements (Box 192, Folder 1)
    - Book Catalogues (Box 192, Folder 2)
    - Book Catalogues (Box 192, Folder 3)
    - Book Catalogues (Box 192, Folder 4)
- Photographs, Series 6; Boxes 193-194
  The series consists of photographs of Peter Fallon, Fallon and family, and Fallon with various authors and poets. There are also publicity photographs of Gallery Press authors and a set of photographs by Mike Bunn for The Writers: A Sense of Ireland published by O'Brien Press. These photographs are denoted as (O'Brien).
  - Peter Fallon
  - Fallon, Peter (alone) (Box 193, Folder 1)
  - Fallon, Peter and family (Box 193, Folder 2)
  - Fallon, Peter (youth) (Box 193, Folder 3)
  - Fallon Peter with Beatrice Behan (Box 193, Folder 4)
  - Fallon, Peter with Wendell Berry (Box 193, Folder 5)
  - Fallon, Peter with Eamon Carr (Box 193, Folder 6)
  - Fallon, Peter with Seamus Deane (Box 193, Folder 7)
  - Fallon, Peter with James Dickey (Box 193, Folder 8)
  - Fallon, Peter with Tim Engelland (Box 193, Folder 9)
  - Fallon, Peter with Brian Friel (Box 193, Folder 10)
  - Fallon, Peter with Seamus Heaney (Box 193, Folder 11)
  - Heaney, Seamus with Richard Ford (Box 193, Folder 12)
  - Fallon, Peter with Brendan Kennelly (Box 193, Folder 13)
  - Fallon, Peter with Joan McBreen (Box 193, Folder 14)
  - Fallon, Peter with John McPhee (Box 193, Folder 15)
  - Fallon, Peter with John Montague (Box 193, Folder 16)
  - Fallon, Peter with Paul Muldoon (Box 193, Folder 17)
  - Fallon, Peter with Publishers (Box 193, Folder 18)
  - Fallon, Peter with Ron Schuchard (Box 193, Folder 19)
  - Fallon, Peter with Gary Snyder (Box 193, Folder 20)
  - Fallon, Peter with Masazumi Taraiwa (Box 193, Folder 21)
  - Fallon, Peter with Loudon Wainwright III (Box 193, Folder 22)
  - Group Shots with Peter Fallon
  - Fallon, Peter with Tara Telephone (Box 193, Folder 23)
  - Fallon, Peter with Deerfield Press (Box 193, Folder 24)
  - Fallon, Peter with others, SF 1983 (Box 193, Folder 25)
  - Fallon, Peter with Thomas Kilroy, Gerald Dawe, and Dorothea Melvoin, Kenny's Galway, 1985 (Box 193, Folder 26)
  - Fallon, Peter and Jean with others, January. 4, 1986 (Fallon Wedding) (Box 193, Folder 27)
  - Fallon, Peter with others, Irish Writer's Conference, 1991 (Box 193, Folder 28)
  - Fallon, Peter with Derek Mahon, Brian Friel, and others, NYC, 1992 (Box 193, Folder 29)
  - Fallon, Peter with Seamus Heaney, Marie Heaney, and John Kelly, NYC, 1995 (Box 193, Folder 30)
  - Fallon, Peter with Pres. Mary Robinson and others, Abbey Theatre, July 4, 1995 (Box 193, Folder 31)
  - Fallon, Peter with Seamus Heaney and others, Stockholm, 1995 (Box 193, Folder 32)
  - Fallon, Peter with others, Carrick-On-Suir, 1997 (Box 193, Folder 33)
  - Fallon, Peter with Nuala Ní Dhomhnaill, Michael Longley, Seamus Heaney, and Paul Muldoon, Princeton, 1998 (Box 193, Folder 34)
  - Group Shots without Peter Fallon by Event
  - Abbey Theatre, Dublin, 1995 (Box 193, Folder 35)
  - Dublin Arts Festival, 1971 (Box 193, Folder 36)
  - Dublin, 1983 (Box 193, Folder 37)
  - Eileán Ní Chuilleanáin, Medbh McGuckian, and Nuala Ní Dhomhnaill, September 1999 (Box 193, Folder 38)
  - Listowel Writer's Week, June, 1976 (Box 193, Folder 39)
  - Tailer's Hall, Dublin (Box 193, Folder 40)
  - Single Shots
  - Archer, Nuala (Box 194, Folder 1)
  - Banville, John (O'Brien) (Box OP87)
  - Beckett, Samuel ( Waiting for Godot photo) (O'Brien) (Box OP88)
  - Boland, Eavan (O'Brien) (Box OP89)
  - Cannon, Moya (Box 194, Folder 2)
  - Cannon, Moya; Derek Mahon; Richard Murphy; Eiléan Ní Chuilleanáin (contact sheet) [photos by Lesley Doyle] (Box OP90)
  - Carr, Marina (Box 194, Folder 4)
  - Carson, Ciaran (Box 194, Folder 5)
  - Clifton, Harry (Box 194, Folder 6)
  - Coady, Michael (Box 194, Folder 7)
  - Dawe, Gerald (Box 194, Folder 8)
  - Deane, Seamus (Box 194, Folder 9)
  - Deane, Seamus [2] (O'Brien) (Box OP91)
  - Dunne, Seán (Box 194, Folder 10)
  - Durcan, Paul (Box 194, Folder 11)
  - Durcan, Paul (Box OP92)
  - Ennis, John (Box 194, Folder 12)
  - Fouere, Olwen (Box 194, Folder 13)
  - Friel, Brian (Box 194, Folder 14)
  - Friel, Brian (O'Brien) (Box OP93)
  - Glavin, Anthony (Box 194, Folder 15)
  - Grennan, Eamon (Box 194, Folder 16)
  - Groarke, Vona (Box 194, Folder 17)
  - Groarke, Vona (Box OP94)
  - Hardie, Kerry (Box 194, Folder 18)
  - Hartnett, Michael (Box 194, Folder 19)
  - Harvey, Francis (Box 194, Folder 20)
  - Healy, Dermot (Box 194, Folder 21)
  - Heaney, Seamus (Box 194, Folder 22)
  - Heaney, Seamus (O'Brien) (Box OP95)
  - Heaney, Seamus (O'Brien; Photo did not appear in book) (Box OP96)
  - Hewitt, John (O'Brien) (Box OP97)
  - Higgins, Aidan (O'Brien) (Box OP98)
  - Hughes, John (Box 194, Folder 23)
  - Hutchinson, Pearse (Box 194, Folder 24)
  - Johnston, Denis (O'Brien) (Box OP99)
  - Jordan, Neil (O'Brien) (Box OP100)
  - Kane. Michael (Box 194, Folder 25)
  - Kennelly, Brendan (Box 194, Folder 26)
  - Kennelly, Brendan (O'Brien) (Box OP101)
  - Kiely, Benedict (O'Brien) (Box OP102)
  - Kilroy, Tom (Box 194, Folder 27)
  - Kilroy, Thomas (O'Brien) (Box OP103)
  - Kinsella, Tom (Box 194, Folder 28)
  - Kinsella, Thomas [2] (O'Brien) (Box OP104)
  - Lavin, Mary (O'Brien) (Box OP105)
  - Longley, Michael (Box 194, Folder 29)
  - Longley, Michael (O'Brien) (Box OP106)
  - Lysaght, Seán (Box 194, Folder 30)
  - McCabe, Eugene (Box 194, Folder 34)
  - McCarthy, Thomas (O'Brien) (Box OP107)
  - McGough, Roger (Box 194, Folder 35)
  - McGuckian, Medbh (Box 194, Folder 36)
  - McGuinness, Frank (Box 194, Folder 37)
  - Mac Siomóin, Tomás (O'Brien) (Box OP108)
  - Mac Intyre, Tom (Box 194, Folder 38)
  - Mahon, Derek [See also: Cannon, Moya] (Box 194, Folder 39)
  - Mathews, Aidan Carl (Box 194, Folder 40)
  - Mathews, Aidan Carl (O'Brien) (Box OP109)
  - Meehan, Paula (Box 194, Folder 41)
  - Montague, John (Box 194, Folder 42)
  - Moore, Christy (Box 194, Folder 43)
  - Morgan, Edwin (Box 194, Folder 44)
  - Morrow, John (O'Brien) (Box OP110)
  - Muldoon, Paul (Box 194, Folder 45)
  - Muldoon, Paul (O'Brien) (Box OP111)
  - Murphy, Richard [See also: Cannon, Moya] (Box 194, Folder 46)
  - Murphy, Thomas (Box 194, Folder 47)
  - Murphy, Thomas (Box OP112)
  - Mycue, Edward (Box 194, Folder 48)
  - Ní Chuilleanáin, Eiléan [See also: Cannon, Moya] (Box 194, Folder 49)
  - Ní Chuilleanáin, Eiléan (O'Brien) (Box OP113)
  - Ni Dhomhnaill, Nuala (Box 194, Folder 50)
  - O'Callaghan, Conor (Box 194, Folder 51)
  - O'Direain, Mairtin (Box 194, Folder 52)
  - O'Donoghue, Bernard (Box 194, Folder 53)
  - Ó Faoláin, Seán (O'Brien) (Box OP114)
  - O'Flaherty, Liam (O'Brien) (Box OP115)
  - O'Grady, Desmond (O'Brien) (Box 194, Folder 54)
  - O'Grady, Desmond (O'Brien) (Box OP116)
  - Ó Muirthile, Liam (O'Brien) (Box OP117)
  - Ó Searcaigh, Cathal (O'Brien) (Box OP118)
  - Ó Siadhail, Mícheál (O'Brien) (Box OP119)
  - Ó Tuama, Seán (O'Brien) (Box OP120)
  - Ormsby, Frank (Box 194, Folder 55)
  - Ormsby, Frank(O'Brien) (Box OP121)
  - Parker, Stewart (O'Brien) (Box OP122)
  - Paulin, Tom (O'Brien) (Box OP123)
  - Plunkett, James (O'Brien; Photo did not appear in book) (Box OP124)
  - Reardon, Daniel (Box OP125)
  - Robinson, Mary (President) (Box 194, Folder 56)
  - W. R. Rodgers (Box 194, Folder 57)
  - Rooney-Cespedes, Aidan (Box 194, Folder 58)
  - Simmons, James (Box 194, Folder 59)
  - Sirr, Peter (Box 194, Folder 60)
  - Stuart, Francis (O'Brien) (Box OP126)
  - Trevor, William (O'Brien) (Box OP127)
  - Vonegut, Kurt (Box 194, Folder 61)
  - Wheatley, David (Box 194, Folder 62)
  - Misc. (non-people) (Box 194, Folder 63)
- Ephemera, Series 7; Box 195
  - Gallery Press rubber stamp (Box 195, Folder 1)
  - Gallery Press button (Box 195, Folder 2)
  - Gallery Press T-shirt (Box 195, Folder 3)
- Unprocessed additions, Series 8; Boxes 196 - 224
  Restrictions on Access
  Special restrictions apply: Correspondence from Seamus Heaney is closed to researchers.
  - Banville, John, God's Gift (Box 196, Folder -)
  - Boland, Rosita, Dissecting the Heart (Box 196, Folder -)
  - Cannon, Moy, Oar (Box 196, Folder -)
  - Carr, Marina, Ariel (Box 196, Folder -)
  - Carr, Marina, By the Bog of Cats (Box 196, Folder -)
  - Carr Marina, On Rafferty's Hill (Box 197, Folder -)
  - Carr, Marina, Portia Coughlan (Box 197, Folder -)
  - Carson, Ciaran, The Alexandrine Plan (Box 197, Folder -)
  - Carson, Ciaran, The Ballad of HMS Belfast (Box 198, Folder -)
  - Carson, Ciaran, Belfast Confetti (Box 198, Folder -)
  - Carson, Ciaran, Breaking News (Box 198, Folder -)
  - Carson, Ciaran, Fishing for Amber (Box 198, Folder -)
  - Carson, Ciaran, The Midnight Court (Box 198, Folder -)
  - Carson, Ciaran, The New Estate and Other Poems (Box 198, Folder -)
  - Carson, Ciaran, The Twelfth of Never (Box 198, Folder -)
  - Cassidy, Lar (Box 198, Folder -)
  - Christmas cards (Box 198, Folder -)
  - Clerkin, Sean (Box 198, Folder -)
  - Clifton, Harry (Box 199, Folder -)
  - Coady, Michael (Box 199, Folder -)
  - Coady, Michael, All Souls (Box 199, Folder -)
  - Coady, Michael, Oven Lane (Box 199, Folder -)
  - Dawe, Gerald, Lake Geneva (Box 199, Folder -)
  - Dawe, Gerald, The Morning Train (Box 199, Folder -)
  - Deane, Seamus (Box 200, Folder -)
  - Fallon, Padraic (Box 200, Folder -)
  - Fallon, Peter, The Georgics [1 of 2] (Box 200, Folder -)
  - Fallon, Peter, The Georgics [2 of 2] (Box 201, Folder -)
  - Fallon, Peter, News of the World (Box 202, Folder -)
  - Fallon, Peter, Terry Flynn (Box 202, Folder -)
  - French, Tom (Box 202, Folder -)
  - French, Tom, Touching the Bones (Box 202, Folder -)
  - Friel, Brian (Box 203, Folder -)
  - Friel, Brian, Molly Sweeney (Box 203, Folder -)
  - Friel, Brian, Three Plays After (Box 203, Folder -)
  - Friel, Brian, Uncle Vanya (Box 203, Folder -)
  - Friel, Brian, The Yalta Game (Box 203, Folder -)
  - Gillis, Alan, Somebody Somewhere (Box 203, Folder -)
  - Goldsmith, Oliver, Deserted Village (Box 204, Folder -)
  - Grennan, Eamon (Box 204, Folder -)
  - Grennan, Eamon, The Quick of It (Box 204, Folder -)
  - Grennan, Eamon, Selected and New Poems (Box 204, Folder -)
  - Grennan, Eamon, Still Life with Waterfall (Box 205, Folder -)
  - Groarke, Vona (Box 205, Folder -)
  - Groarke, Vona, Flight (Box 205, Folder -)
  - Groarke, Vona, Other People's Houses (Box 205, Folder -)
  - Hardie, Kerry (Box 205, Folder -)
  - Hardie, Kerry, Cry for the Hot Belly (Box 206, Folder -)
  - Hardie, Kerry, The Sky Didn't Fall (Box 206, Folder -)
  - Hartnett, Michael, Collected Poems (Box 206, Folder -)
  - Hartnett Michael, O Rathaille (Box 206, Folder -)
  - Hartnett, Michael, translations (Box 206, Folder -)
  - Healy, Dermot, The Reed Bed (Box 207, Folder -)
  - Healy, Dermot, What the Hammer (Box 207, Folder -)
  - Heaney, Seamus, The Midnight Verdict (Box 207, Folder -)
  - Heaney, Seamus, The Stick (Box 207, Folder -)
  - Hughes, John (Box 207, Folder -)
  - Hughes, Ted, clippings (Box 207, Folder -)
  - Hutchinson, Pearse, Collected Poems [1 of 2] (Box 207, Folder -)
  - Hutchinson, Pearse, Collected Poems [2 of 2] (Box 208, Folder -)
  - Hutchinson, Pearse, Done Into English (Box 208, Folder -)
  - Kilroy, Thomas, Death and Resurrection (Box 208, Folder -)
  - Kilroy, Thomas, Ghosts (Box 208, Folder -)
  - Kilroy, Thomas, My Scandalous Life (Box 209, Folder -)
  - Kilroy, Thomas, The Shape of Metal (Box 209, Folder -)
  - Kilroy, Thomas, Tea and Sex and Shakespeare (Box 209, Folder -)
  - Lysaght, Sean (Box 209, Folder -)
  - Lysaght, Sean, Scarecrow (Box 210, Folder -)
  - MacDonogh, Patrick, Poems (Box 210, Folder -)
  - MacIntyre, Tom (Box 210, Folder -)
  - Mahon, Derek, Birds (Box 210, Folder -)
  - Mahon, Derek, Collected Poems [1 of 2] (Box 210, Folder -)
  - Mahon, Derek, Collected Poems [2 of 2] (Box 211, Folder -)
  - Mahon, Derek, Cyrano de Bergerac (Box 211, Folder -)
  - Mahon, Derek, Resistance Days (Box 211, Folder -)
  - Mahon, Derek, Roman Script (Box 211, Folder -)
  - Mahon, Derek, Seaside Cemetery (Box 212, Folder -)
  - Mahon, Derek, Words in the Air (Box 212, Folder -)
  - McAuliffe, John (Box 212, Folder -)
  - McCabe, Eugene, Tales from the Poorhouse (Box 212, Folder -)
  - McGuckian, Medbh [1 of 2] (Box 212, Folder -)
  - McGuckian, Medbh [2 of 2] (Box 213, Folder -)
  - McGuckian, Medbh, The Book of the Angel (Box 213, Folder -)
  - McGuckian, Medbh, Drawing Ballerinas (Box 213, Folder -)
  - McGuckian, Medbh, The Face of the Earth (Box 213, Folder -)
  - McGuckian, Medbh, Had I a Thousand Lives (Box 213, Folder -)
  - McGuckian, Medbh, Shelmalier [1 of 2] (Box 213, Folder -)
  - McGuckian, Medbh, Shelmalier [2 of 2] (Box 214, Folder -)
  - McGuinness, Frank, The Sea with No Ships (Box 214, Folder -)
  - McGuinness, Frank, The Stone Jug (Box 214, Folder -)
  - Meehan, Paula (Box 214, Folder -)
  - Miscellaneous covers (Box 214, Folder -)
  - Modern American Poets Series [MAPS] (Box 214, Folder -)
  - Montague, John (Box 214, Folder -)
  - Montague, John, Drunken Sailor (Box 215, Folder -)
  - Montague, John, Selected Poems (Box 215, Folder -)
  - Montague, John, Smashing the Piano (Box 215, Folder -)
  - Muldoon, Paul (Box 215, Folder -)
  - Muldoon, Paul, The Birds (Box 215, Folder -)
  - Murphy, Richard, Collected Poems (Box 215, Folder -)
  - Ní Chuilleanáin, Eiléan, The Woman who Married the Reindeer [1 of 2] (Box 215, Folder -)
  - Ní Chuilleanáin, Eiléan, The Woman who Married the Reindeer [2 of 2] (Box 216, Folder -)
  - Ní Dhomhnaill, Nuala, The Waterhouse (Box 216, Folder -)
  - Nolan, Jim (Box 216, Folder -)
  - Nolan, Jim, Blackwater Angel (Box 216, Folder -)
  - Nolan, Jim, The Salvage Shop [1 of 2] (Box 216, Folder -)
  - Nolan, Jim, The Salvage Shop [2 of 2] (Box 217, Folder -)
  - O'Callaghan, Conor (Box 217, Folder -)
  - O'Callaghan, Conor, Seatown (Box 217, Folder -)
  - O'Reilly, Phil, book (Box 217, Folder -)
  - Quinn, Justin (Box 217, Folder -)
  - Readings (Box 217, Folder -)
  - Rooney, Aidan, Day Release [1 of 2] (Box 217, Folder -)
  - Rooney, Aidan, Day Release [2 of 2] (Box 218, Folder -)
  - Series (Box 218, Folder -)
  - Simmons, James (Box 218, Folder -)
  - Sirr, Peter (Box 218, Folder -)
  - Sirr, Peter, Bring Everything (Box 218, Folder -)
  - Sirr, Peter, Nonetheless (Box 218, Folder -)
  - Wheatley, David (Box 218, Folder -)
  - Wheatley, David, Mangan (Box 219, Folder -)
  - Wheatley, David, Misery Hill (Box 219, Folder -)
  - Heaney, Seamus, bibliography [1 of 4] (Box 220, Folder -)
  - Heaney, Seamus, bibliography [2 of 4] (Box 221, Folder -)
  - Heaney, Seamus, bibliography [3 of 4] (Box 222, Folder -)
  - Heaney, Seamus, bibliography [4 of 4] (Box 223, Folder -)
  - Heaney, Seamus, correspondence [RESTRICTED] (Box 224, Folder -)